Guide to the Robert S. Rankin Papers, 1898 - 1977 (bulk 1927 - 1976) UA.29.02.0078
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Robert S. Rankin papers
1898 - 1977 (bulk 1927 - 1976)
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Rankin, Robert S. (Robert Stanley), 1899-
UA.29.02.0078
30 Linear Feet
Robert Stanley Rankin (1899-1976) taught political science at Duke beginning in 1927 and was chairman of the political science department from 1949 to 1964. He retired from teaching in 1969. The collection includes departmental records, correspondence, reports, notes, student papers, questionnaires, publications, and other materials of Robert S. Rankin and the Duke University Department of Political Science. English.
20,000 Items
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Records, such as search committee files or others pertaining to employment where individuals are identified, are closed for 70 years.
In accordance with the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 as amended, Duke University permits students to inspect their education records and limits the disclosure of personally identifiable information from education records.
Unprocessed materials are closed pending processing.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Provenance
The Robert S. Rankin Papers was received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1977, 2001.
Biographical Note
Robert Stanley Rankin (1899-1976), educator and political scientist, was born in Tusculum, TN, and educated at Tusculum College. He received graduate degrees at Princeton and returned to Tusculum as a political science professor in 1924. His career at Duke began in 1927 as assistant professor of political science. Rankin was appointed associate professor in 1929, professor in 1934, and was chairman of the political science department from 1949 to 1964. He was co-founder and president (1931) of the Southern Political Science Association. Active in local and national politics, he served on the Durham, NC City Council from 1955 to 1960. President Eisenhower appointed him to the U.S. Commission on Civil Rights in 1960, where he served for 16 years. He retired from teaching in 1969. The Robert S. Rankin Civil Rights Library at the U.S. Commission on Civil Rights, established in 1960, was named for Rankin in 1976.
Collection Overview
The collection includes departmental records, correspondence, reports, notes, student papers, questionnaires, publications, and other materials of Robert S. Rankin and the Duke University Department of Political Science, circa 1927-1977.
Related Material
Robert S. Rankin Papers
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Dorothy Newsom Rankin Papers
Duke University Archives
Tusculum College; Duke University -- Faculty; Rankin, Robert S. (Robert Stanley), 1899-; Southern Political Science Association; Duke University. Department of Political Science; Rankin, Robert S. (Robert Stanley), 1899-
- Robert S. Rankin Department of Political Science Records, circa 1927-1977
  Scope and Contents note
  This series includes files of departmental records, correspondence, reports, notes, student papers, questionnaires, publications, and other materials of Robert S. Rankin and the Duke University Department of Political Science.
  The materials in this series appear to have been edited and rearranged by Rankin's wife, Dorothy Newsom Rankin. In many instances, there are interpretive notes written by Mrs. Rankin on the outsides of file folders. Some of the folder titles appear to be Rankin's original titles, while other titles and dates seem to have been provided by Mrs. Rankin. Some of the folders were unlabeled and have been given titles by University Archives staff. In some instances, no common subject for the materials in the folders could be ascertained, and those folders have not been supplied titles and remain unlabeled.
  There are extensive handwritten notes by Mrs. Rankin regarding these materials in the University Archives Collection File. Please consult a University Archives staff member to see these notes.
  - Course Material, circa 1927-circa 1976
    - Preliminary Examination: American Government and Constitutional Law, 1968 Feb. (Box 1)
    - The Viewpoint of Justice Holmes (Box 1)
    - The American Presidency (Box 1)
    - Materials for Constitutional Law (Box 1)
    - Class Materials (Box 1)
    - Class: Constitutional Law (Box 1)
    - Class Lectures (Box 1)
    - Concerning R.S.R.'s Classes (Box 1)
    - R.S.R.: Class Lectures and Materials, mainly the Constitutional Convention (Box 1)
    - Class: American Government, additional lecture notes (Box 1)
    - Class: American Political Institutions, lecture notes (Box 1)
    - Class Notes: Pardon and Rendition (Box 1)
    - Class Lecture Materials (Box 1)
    - Class Notes: Due Process and Equal Protection (Box 1)
    - Class Notes: Judicial Review and Justice in the Courts (Box 1)
    - Class Notes: Right to Demonstrate (Box 1)
    - Class Notes: Unreasonable Search and Seizure (Box 1)
    - Class Lectures (Box 1)
    - Class Notes: First Amendment (Box 1)
    - Seminar Notes (Box 1)
    - Unlabeled (Box 1)
    - Class Notes: Double Jeopardy (Box 1)
    - Class Notes: Constitutional Law and the Court Systems (Box 1)
    - Unlabeled (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous Class Notes (Box 1)
    - Class: Economics 225 (Box 1)
    - Class Notes: State Government (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous Lectures and Class Notes (Box 1)
    - Unlabeled (Box 1)
    - Municipal Government (Box 1)
    - Municipal Administration (Box 1)
    - R.S.R.'s Teaching (Box 1)
    - Unlabeled (Box 1)
    - Unlabeled (Box 1)
    - Material on Tort Liability in N.C. (Box 1)
    - Political Science 226 (Box 1)
    - Sample Ballots (Box 1)
  - Publications, 1946-1970 (Box 2)
    - Race and the Tobacco Industry, 1970 (Box 2)
    - Political Science in the South, 1946 (Box 2)
    - The Impact of Civil Rights Upon 20th Century Federalism, 1963 (Box 2)
    - Hawaii Under Martial Law, 1943 (Box 2)
    - Martial Law and the Writ of Habeas Corpus in Hawaii, 1944 (Box 2)
  - Research and Writings, 1934-circa 1957
    - A.B. Degree Examinations (History, Government, and Economics), 1934-1935 (Box 2)
    - British Information Services Reference Division, 1950 Jan. (Box 2)
    - Information on Kansas State Finance, 1947 (Box 2)
    - R.S.R.'s Study of Grants-in-aid of the Canadian Government, circa 1947 (Box 2)
    - Canadian Fiscal Policy Notes, circa 1957 (1 of 2) (Box 2)
    - Canadian Fiscal Policy Notes, circa 1957 (2 of 2) (Box 2)
  - Case Briefs, circa 1930-circa 1970
    - Case Briefs (1 of 4) (Box 2)
    - Case Briefs (2 of 4) (Box 2)
    - Case Briefs (3 of 4) (Box 2)
    - Case Briefs (4 of 4) (Box 2)
  - Student Papers, circa 1930-1970 (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous Notes on Presidential Advisors (Box 3)
    - Student Papers: Charles Pinckney: Constitution Maker by Fred. J. Fletcher, 1965, and General Charles Cotesworth Pinckney by Peter J. Liacouras, 1961 (Box 3)
    - Donna K. Smith Masters Thesis, 1966 (Box 3)
    - Course 230 (American Political Institutions) Reading List, 1954-1955 (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous Presidential Advisors Information (Box 3)
    - Student Papers: Presidential Advisors, 1953-1958 (Box 3)
    - Student Papers: Presidential Advisors, paper notes (Box 3)
    - Student Papers: Presidential Advisors: Coolidge, Cleveland, Buchanan, Arthur, Adams, John Quincy Adams, 1949 (Box 3)
    - Student Papers: Presidential Advisors: Harding, Grant, Fillmore, Hoover, Jackson, Jefferson, Johnson, 1949 (Box 3)
    - Student Papers: Presidential Advisors: Hayes, 1949 (Box 3)
    - Student Papers: Presidential Advisors: FDR, Pierce, Monroe, 1949 (Box 3)
    - Student Papers: Presidential Advisors: McKinley, Madison, Lincoln, Polk, Wilson, 1949 (Box 3)
    - Student Papers: Presidential Advisors: Washington, Taft, Theodore Roosevelt, 1949 (Box 3)
    - Assorted Student Papers, 1936, 1939 (Box 3)
    - Assorted Student Papers, circa 1940-1949 (1 of 2) (Box 3)
    - Assorted Student Papers, circa 1940-1949 (2 of 2) (Box 3)
    - Assorted Student Papers, 1953, 1957 (Box 3)
    - Assorted Student Papers, 1962-1966 (Box 3)
    - Assorted Student Papers, 1970 (Box 3)
    - Assorted Student Papers, undated (1 of 3) (Box 3)
    - Assorted Student Papers, undated (2 of 3) (Box 3)
    - Assorted Student Papers, undated (3 of 3) (Box 3)
  - Survey: Study of Political Selection and Advancement, 1938-1940 (Box 4)
    - Questionnaire Information (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous Materials (Box 4)
    - Questionnaire: Confirmations of Receipt, 1938 (Box 4)
    - Questionnaire: Refusals to Complete, 1938 (Box 4)
    - Questionnaire: Completed and Returned Copies, 1938 (1 of 3) (Box 4)
    - Questionnaire: Completed and Returned Copies, 1938 (2 of 3) (Box 4)
    - Questionnaire: Completed and Returned Copies, 1938 (3 of 3) (Box 4)
    - Questionnaire: Confirmations of Receipt, 1939 (Box 4)
    - Questionnaire: Refusals to Complete, 1939 (1 of 2) (Box 4)
    - Questionnaire: Refusals to Complete, 1939 (2 of 2) (Box 4)
    - Questionnaire: Completed and Returned Copies, 1939 (1 of 5) (Box 4)
    - Questionnaire: Completed and Returned Copies, 1939 (2 of 5) (Box 4)
    - Questionnaire: Completed and Returned Copies, 1939 (3 of 5) (Box 4)
    - Questionnaire: Completed and Returned Copies, 1939 (4 of 5) (Box 4)
    - Questionnaire: Completed and Returned Copies, 1939 (5 of 5) (Box 4)
    - Questionnaire: Confirmations of Receipt, 1940 (Box 4)
    - Questionnaire: Refusals to Complete, 1940 (Box 4)
    - Questionnaire: Completed and Returned, 1940 (1 of 2) (Box 4)
    - Questionnaire: Completed and Returned, 1940 (2 of 2) (Box 4)
    - Questionnaire: Completed but Undated Questionnaires (1 of 2) (Box 4)
    - Questionnaire: Completed but Undated Questionnaires (2 of 2) (Box 4)
    - Questionnaire: Tallies of Answers (Box 4)
    - Questionnaire: Empty Envelopes Addressed to Potential Subjects (Box 4)
    - Questionnaire: Empty Return Envelopes (Box 4)
  - North Carolina Book, circa 1955 (Box 5)
    - General-North Carolina (Box 5)
    - Chapter One, The State and Its People (1 of 2) (Box 5)
    - Chapter One, The State and Its People (2 of 2) (Box 5)
    - Chapter Two, The State Constitution (1 of 2) (Box 5)
    - Chapter Two, The State Constitution (2 of 2) i.e. The Judiciary (Box 5)
    - Chapter Four, The Legislature: Composition and Organization (Box 5)
    - Chapters Four and Five, The Legislature (Box 5)
    - Chapter Five, The Legislature: Powers and Procedure (Box 5)
    - Chapter Eight, The Revenue System (Box 5)
    - Chapter Nine, Financial Administration (Box 5)
    - Chapter Ten, Personnel Administration (1 of 2) (Box 5)
    - Chapter Ten, Personnel Administration (2 of 2) (Box 5)
    - Chapter Eleven, The Courts (Box 5)
    - Chapter Twelve, Law Enforcement (Box 5)
    - Chapter Thirteen, Education (Box 5)
    - Chapter Fifteen, Intergovernmental Relations (Box 5)
    - Chapter Sixteen, Agriculture (Box 5)
    - Chapter Nineteen, Labor (Box 5)
    - Chapter Twenty-one, Professional Licensing (Box 5)
    - Chapter Twenty-two, State Planning and Development (1 of 2) (Box 5)
    - Chapter Twenty-two, State Planning and Development (2 of 2) (Box 5)
    - North Carolina Book: Student Paper, The North Carolina Highway System (Box 5)
    - North Carolina Book: Weight Limits, Truck Weight Limits, Weighing Stations (Box 5)
    - North Carolina Book: Defense (Box 5)
    - North Carolina Book: News Clippings (1 of 3) (Box 5)
    - North Carolina Book: News Clippings (2 of 3) (Box 5)
    - North Carolina Book: News Clippings (3 of 3) (Box 5)
    - North Carolina Book: Unlabeled Material (1 of 3) (Box 5)
    - North Carolina Book: Unlabeled Material (2 of 3) (Box 5)
    - North Carolina Book: Unlabeled Material (3 of 3) (Box 5)
    - North Carolina Book: Miscellaneous Material (Box 5)
  - Literature, 1932-1975 (Box 6)
    - Booklets on State Government (1 of 2) (Box 6)
    - Booklets on State Government (2 of 2) (Box 6)
    - Booklets on Constitutional Law (Box 6)
    - Booklets on Municipal Government (Box 6)
    - Booklets on American Government (1 of 3) (Box 6)
    - Booklets on American Government (2 of 3) (Box 6)
    - Booklets on American Government (3 of 3) (Box 6)
    - Booklets on Apportionment (1 of 2) (Box 6)
    - Booklets on Apportionment (2 of 2) (Box 6)
    - Booklets on Foreign Policy (Box 6)
    - Booklets on Social Security (Box 6)
    - Booklets on Law Enforcement and Capital Punishment (Box 6)
    - Booklets on Civil Rights and the Bill of Rights (Box 6)
    - Sample Questions from the Examination for Foreign Service Officer (Box 6)
    - Money and Politics (Box 6)
    - The Nomination of Joe Bottom: Analysis of a Committee Decision to Nominate a U.S. (Box 6)
    - Senator (Box 6)
    - Religion and American Society: A Statement of Principles (Box 6)
    - American Council of Learned Societies (ACLS) Newsletter, 1975 Spring-Summer (Box 6)
    - Proposed Consolidation of City and County Government by Durham Chamber of Commerce, 1932 Dec. (Box 6)
    - Hearings/Reports/Speeches of the U.S. Senate (Box 6)
    - Reports on Candidates for Election: Seattle, 1948 and Cleveland, 1947 (Box 6)
    - Annual Report of the Citizens Conference on State Legislatures, 1969 (Box 6)
    - Conference on State Information Systems at the Institute on State Programming, for the 70s, UNC-Chapel Hill, 1968 (Box 6)
    - Eugenical Sterilization in North Carolina (Box 6)
    - Political Studies Program Research Reports: A Series of Student Papers (Box 6)
    - Reprint from Michigan State University's Business Topic: A Legal and Economic Note on Price-Fixing (Box 6)
    - Report of the Municipal Government Study Commission of the NC General Assembly (Box 6)
    - Civil Defense: A Bibliographic Survey, 1960-1967 (Box 6)
    - Recently Acquired/Catalogued Collections of the Manuscript Department of Perkins Library, 1975 (Box 6)
    - The Freedom to be Free! The Faculty Forum, 1967 Nov. (Box 6)
    - Program for Action, a Report of the Virginia Metropolitan Areas Study Commission, 1967 (Box 6)
    - NSA Professional Qualification Test, 1967 (Box 6)
    - Standards Relating to the Urban Police Function, 1973-1974 (Box 6)
    - Publications by Gus Hall (Box 6)
    - Constitutional Revision in Theory and Practice (Box 6)
    - Man on Earth, Volume 1 Number 1, 1964 (Box 6)
    - The Vice Presidency: Its Institutional Evolution and Contemporary Status (Box 6)
    - UVa Bulletin, 1968-1969 (Box 6)
    - Public Administration in the South (Box 6)
    - Duke University Faculty Handbook, 1968 (Box 6)
    - Newspaper Clipping from 1964 Sept. 20 (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous Material (Box 6)
  - Correspondence and Subject Files, 1937-1973 (Box 7)
    - Ball, Margaret, 1962-1964 (Box 7)
    - Braibanti, Ralph, 1952-1964 (Box 7)
    - Connery, Robert H., 1948-1965 (Box 7)
    - Cheek, Roma S., 1950-1963 (Box 7)
    - Cole, R. Taylor, 1951-1963 (Box 7)
    - University Curriculum Committee, 1962 (Box 7)
    - Committee on Courses of Instruction and Schedule Committee (Box 7)
    - Dozier, John, 1951-1963 (Box 7)
    - Award Applications, Ford Foundation Grant on Research in Public Affairs (Box 7)
    - Minutes, Ford Foundation Grant on Research in Public Affairs (Box 7)
    - Payments, Ford Summer Conference, 1961-1964 (Box 7)
    - Expenses, Conference on Teaching Political Science, 1962-1963 (Box 7)
    - Conference on Teaching, Ford Foundation Grant for Research in Public Affairs (Box 7)
    - Committee on Faculty Reorganization, 1961-1962 (Box 7)
    - Faculty Advisor System, 1962-1964 (Box 7)
    - Faculty Fringe Benefits, 1963 (Box 7)
    - Graduate Affairs Committee of the University Planning Committee, 1963 (Box 7)
    - Honors Program: Senior Seminar, 1960-1963 (Box 7)
    - Hall, Hugh M., 1952-1965 (Box 7)
    - Hallowell, John H., 1949-1964 (Box 7)
    - Hobbs, Marcus, 1951-1963 (Box 7)
    - Hopkins, Everett H., 1963 (Box 7)
    - Henricksen, G. C. (Box 7)
    - Departmental Part-Time Instructors, 1961-1964 (Box 7)
    - Committee on Introductory Courses, 1963-1964 (Box 7)
    - Jewell, Malcolm, 1962-1963 (Box 7)
    - Kearney, Robert N., 1963 (Box 7)
    - Kline, Earl, 1964 (Box 7)
    - Kulski, W. W., 1963 (Box 7)
    - Leach, Richard H., 1955-1964 (Box 7)
    - Lewis, Harold W., 1963-1964 (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 7)
    - Morgan, John A. (Box 7)
    - Minutes, Departmental Meetings, 1963 (Box 7)
    - Paletz, David L. (Box 7)
    - Partridge, Percy H., 1959 (Box 7)
    - Proctor, J. Harris, 1958-1973 (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous: Political Science Department, 1971-1973 (Box 7)
    - Political Science Department (Box 7)
    - Teaching Political Science, 1959 (Box 7)
    - Departmental Recommendations to the Administration, 1957 (Box 7)
    - Simpson, William Hays, 1945-1964 (Box 7)
    - Sindler, Allan P. (Box 7)
    - Departmental Committee on Space Requirements, University Facilities Committee (Box 7)
    - Scholarships, 1963 (Box 7)
    - Proposed Sabbatical Leaves, 1957-1962 (Box 7)
    - Summer Session, 1951-1963 (Box 7)
    - Wheeler, Richard S., 1960-1962 (Box 7)
    - Whitford, W. E., 1950-1964 (Box 7)
    - Wilson, Robert R., 1937-1949 (Box 7)
    - Wilson, Robert R., 1950-1963 (Box 7)
    - Teaching Positions, 1964-1965 (Box 7)
    - Teaching Positions, 1963-1964 and Acknowledgments, 1964-1965 (Box 7)
    - Teaching Positions, 1963-1964 (Box 7)
    - Teaching Positions Available at Various Universities, 1961-1962 (Box 7)
  - Budgets and Financial Statements, 1949-1964 (Box 8)
    - Political Science Budgets, 1950-1954 (Box 8)
    - Political Science Budgets, 1955-1958 (Box 8)
    - Political Science Budgets, 1949-1950, 1961-1964 (Box 8)
    - Financial Statements, Political Science Department, 1954 (Box 8)
    - Financial Statements, Political Science Department, 1955 (Box 8)
    - Financial Statements, Political Science Department, 1956 (1 of 2) (Box 8)
    - Financial Statements, Political Science Department, 1956 (2 of 2) (Box 8)
    - Financial Statements, Political Science Department, 1957 (Box 8)
    - Financial Statements, Political Science Department, 1958 (1 of 2) (Box 8)
    - Financial Statements, Political Science Department, 1958 (2 of 2) (Box 8)
    - Financial Statements, Political Science Department, 1959 (Box 8)
    - Financial Statements, Political Science Department, 1960 (1 of 2) (Box 8)
    - Financial Statements, Political Science Department, 1960 (2 of 2) (Box 8)
    - Financial Statements, Political Science Department, 1961 (Box 8)
    - Financial Statements, Political Science Department, 1962 (1 of 2) (Box 8)
    - Financial Statements, Political Science Department, 1962 (2 of 2) (Box 8)
    - Financial Statements, Political Science Department, 1963 (1 of 2) (Box 8)
    - Financial Statements, Political Science Department, 1963 (2 of 2) (Box 8)
    - Financial Statements, Political Science Department, 1964 (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 8)
  - Correspondence and Subject Files, 1963-1976 (Box 9)
    - John F. Kennedy Sports Memorial Medal, The United States Amateur Athletic Union (Box 9)
    - American Arbitration Association, 1966-1971 (Box 9)
    - American Assembly, 1966-1968 (Box 9)
    - American Government Text and North Carolina Text (Box 9)
    - Athletic Department and Program, 1966, 1976 (Box 9)
    - Atlantic Coast Conference, 1965-1969 (Box 9)
    - Athletic Council, 1963-1973 (Box 9)
    - Duke University Athletic Council, 1965-1976 (Box 9)
    - A Correspondence, 1966-1969 (Box 9)
    - B Correspondence, 1966-1976 (Box 9)
    - Campbell College, 1968-1970 (Box 9)
    - Center for Southern Studies, 1966-1967 (Box 9)
    - City-County Consolidation, 1970 (Box 9)
    - Committee Study of the Board of Trustees of the University of North Carolina, 1965-1967 (Box 9)
    - Compacts of Antiquity: State Constitutions, Seminar at Duke University, 1969 Apr. 21-25 (Box 9)
    - Constitutional Convention of Maryland, 1967 (Box 9)
    - Cosmos Club, 1967-1975 (Box 9)
    - C Correspondence, 1966-1975 (Box 9)
    - ED Davis, 1966-1968 (Box 9)
    - Royal Order of the Dizzy Dozen (Fishing Club of North Carolina Educators), 1970-1975 (Box 9)
    - D Correspondence, 1966-1975 (Box 9)
    - Electoral College: Statement (Box 9)
    - Emory and Henry, 1968 (Box 9)
    - Furman University Speech on Values Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 9)
    - E Correspondence, 1968-1976 (Box 9)
    - F Correspondence, 1966-1974 (Box 9)
    - Georgia Law Review, Mr. Vickery, 1971-1972 (Box 9)
    - Graduate Students, 1966-1969 (Box 9)
    - Stephen A. Graham (Box 9)
    - Rodney Grunes, 1967-1973 (Box 9)
    - G Correspondence, 1966-1976 (Box 9)
    - H Correspondence, 1966-1975 (Box 9)
    - I Correspondence, 1967-1974 (Box 9)
    - John P. Jones, 1966-1972 (Box 9)
    - J Correspondence, 1965-1975 (Box 9)
    - K Correspondence, 1966-1974 (Box 9)
    - N.C. Local Government Study Commission, 1967-1969 (Box 9)
    - L Correspondence, 1966-1972 (Box 9)
    - Meredith College, 1976 (Box 9)
    - Music Box (Sponholz), 1966-1967 (Box 9)
    - Mc Correspondence, 1967-1975 (Box 9)
    - M Correspondence, 1966-1976 (Box 9)
    - Notre Dame Lawyer, 1971-1973 (Box 9)
    - N Correspondence, 1968-1976 (Box 9)
    - Occoneechee Golf Association, 1972 (Box 9)
    - O Correspondence, 1967 (Box 9)
    - Phi Beta Kappa Associates Lectureship Panel, 1971-1976 (Box 9)
    - Phi Beta Kappa Appointment to Committee on Ralph Waldo Emerson, 1969 (Box 9)
    - Phi Kappa Psi Fraternity, 1967-1976 (Box 9)
    - Phi Kappa Alpha, 1967-1968 (Box 9)
    - Proposed Program of Study for Ph.D., 1963-1967 (Box 9)
    - P Correspondence, 1966-1975 (Box 9)
    - Q Correspondence (Box 9)
    - Recommendations, 1966-1969 (Box 10)
    - Retirement (R.S.R.), 1969-1970 (Box 10)
    - Review ( American Political Science Review) of Law and Justice: Essays in Honor of Robert S. Rankin (Box 10)
    - Ph.D. Rooks, Charles S., 1961-1968 (Box 10)
    - Rotary, 1967-1976 (Box 10)
    - Rankin: Personal, 1967-1969, 1973-1976 (Box 10)
    - R Correspondence, 1964, 1966-1975 (Box 10)
    - Shriver, Donald W., 1966-1967 (Box 10)
    - Jerry B. Stone Awards, 1966-1976 (Box 10)
    - Student Rating of Professors (Box 10)
    - Albert Sturm, 1967-1973 (Box 10)
    - S Correspondence, 1965-1976 (Box 10)
    - Tobacco Study (Box 10)
    - Tobacco Study (Box 10)
    - Questionnaire, R. J. Reynolds Tobacco Co. (Box 10)
    - Management (Tobacco Study) (Box 10)
    - Tobacco Study Interviews (Box 10)
    - Tobacco Study Interviews (Box 10)
    - Tobacco Study (Box 10)
    - Questionnaire, American Tobacco Company (Box 10)
    - Tobacco Study Finances, Ford Foundation Grant on Research in Public Affairs (Box 10)
    - T Correspondence, 1966-1975 (Box 10)
    - United States Senate, 1966 (Box 10)
    - U Correspondence, 1966-1973 (Box 10)
    - Sally Jo Vasicko, 1967-1974 (Box 10)
    - V Correspondence (Box 10)
    - Wilson, Robert R., 1968-1975 (Box 10)
    - Wright, Robert R., 1971-1973 (Box 10)
    - W Correspondence, 1966-1975 (Box 10)
    - Z Correspondence, 1968 (Box 10)
    - Copies of letters from Mrs. Robert S. Rankin concerning R.S.R.'s office equipment and early papers (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous Folders, 1938-1968
    - Martial Law writings, 1943-1944 (Box 10)
    - Reapportionment of the House of Representatives: U.S. Congress Committee of the American Political Science Association, circa 1950-1952 (Box 10)
    - Articles, letters, etc. concerning The Presidency in Transition in The Journal of Politics, 1949 Feb. (Box 10)
    - Annual Conference of the N.C. City Manager's Association (North Carolina League of Municipalities), 1959-1960 (Box 10)
    - Pro-Nazi Letter to R.S.R., 1938 (Box 10)
    - Survey of Durham County/City Schools by Duke Political Science Dept., 1947 (Box 10)